<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on eSCAPE</title>
    <link>https://escape-model.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on eSCAPE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Tristan Salles - School of Geosciences - The University of Sydney</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://escape-model.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands-on tutorials</title>
      <link>https://escape-model.github.io/2018/09/hands-on-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://escape-model.github.io/2018/09/hands-on-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>To get some additional info in regards to how to use eSCAPE a series of examples and tutorials is provided in the docker container (Geodels escape-docker) and is also available for download from the eSCAPE-demo repository.
Usage Either via jupyter notebooks or python files.
python run_eSCAPE.py -i input.yml -v  where the run_eSCAPE.py script takes one required argument the input filename and an optional verbose command (-v). To run the script in parallel simply use the mpirun command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Input files</title>
      <link>https://escape-model.github.io/2018/09/input-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://escape-model.github.io/2018/09/input-files/</guid>
      <description>Input files for eSCAPE are based on YAML syntax.
A typical file will look like this:
name: Description of the simulation... domain: filename: [&#39;data/inputfileparameters.vtk&#39;,&#39;Z&#39;] flowdir: 5 bc: &#39;slope&#39; time: start: 0. end: 1000000. tout: 1000. dt: 100. sea: position: 0. curve: &#39;data/sealevel.csv&#39; climate: - start: 0. uniform: 1.0 - start: 500000. map: [&#39;data/inputfileparameters.vtk&#39;,&#39;R&#39;] - start: 500000. uniform: 2.0 tectonic: - start: 0. map: [&#39;data/inputfileparameters.vtk&#39;,&#39;T1&#39;] - start: 100000. uniform: 0. - start: 50000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://escape-model.github.io/2018/09/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://escape-model.github.io/2018/09/installation/</guid>
      <description>Getting started For installation information and documentation visit our Github wiki page which provides a quick guide on the installation dependencies.
API documentation is available from the eSCAPE-API website and a set of examples are available in the eSCAPE-demo repository.
The easiest way to get started is with the Docker container https://hub.docker.com/u/geodels/ using Kitematic. Once Kitematic is installed on your computer, open it and look for Geodels escape-docker via the search menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://escape-model.github.io/2018/09/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://escape-model.github.io/2018/09/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contributions
We welcome all kinds of contributions! Please get in touch if you would like to help out. Everything from code to notebooks to examples and documentation are all equally valuable so please don&amp;rsquo;t feel you can&amp;rsquo;t contribute. To contribute please fork the project make your changes and submit a pull request. We will do our best to work through any issues with you and get your code merged into the main branch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>